好了，他们来了。
开
All right, they're here.
Let's do this.
等等，别的客人呢？
Wait wait, what about
the other guests?
什么别的客人？
大家都在这了
What other guests?
Everyone's here.
-抵押贷款文件呢？
-在这呢
- Do you have the mortgage?
- Yeah, here we go.
我等这一刻30年了
I've been waiting
30 years to do this.
-来吧
-来了
- There you go.
- There we go.
-哦呜
-哦
- Ooh.
-
-S
- Yeah.
- Yay.
房子付清了
The house is now
paid off.
敬给Lynbrook抵押贷款公司
可爱的工作人员
Here's to the wonderful
people
谢谢日历
at Lynbrook Mortgage.
Thanks for the calendars,
你们都可以来亲我的
美国大屁股了
and you can all kiss
my great American ass.
爷爷，爷爷
Grandpa, Grandpa.
哦，对不起，孩子们。
不要说屁股
Oh, oh, sorry, kids.
Don't say ass.
嘿，真好玩
Hey, that was fun.
-
-让我们开个真正的派对
- Yeah!
- Let's have a real party.
玛丽，把咱们的结婚证拿过来
Marie, go get
our marriage license.
好了，可以吃了吗，请问？
All right,
could we eat, please?
-过来，孩子们
-妈，爸，恭喜了
- Come on, kids.
- Ma, Dad, congratulations.
房子已经是你们的产业的一部分
The house becomes
part of your estate
要在以前欧洲，
which in the old country
would be
将传给长子
passed down
to the firstborn son.
要在以前欧洲，
你早进马戏团了
In the old country,
you'd be working in the circus.
猴子服（礼服）可以脱了
Monkey suit's
coming off.
那么，玛丽，怎么了？
So, Marie,
what happened?
我以为你们要开个大型派对庆祝
I thought you were gonna have
a big party to celebrate.
这就是派对。
我做了烤面包
It is a party.
I made bruschetta.
哦，我以为你说
Oh, I thought
when you said
要开个派对指的是
you were having a party
that would include...
我不知道……有朋友参加的那种
I don't know...
some friends.
哦，谁有时间交朋友？
来个魔鬼蛋吧，亲爱的
Oh, who has time for friends?
Have a deviled egg, dear.
什么叫做你没时间交朋友？
What do you mean,
you don't have time for friends?
你和雷蒙德搬过来以后
Well, after you and
Raymond moved in,
我是说，总得有人帮你照顾家里吧
I mean, someone had to help you
raise a family,
所以我们只能牺牲些东西
so we just had
to give up some things.
你的社交生活
Your social life?
我们仍然有社交生活的
We still have
a social life.
吗，罗伯特把魔鬼蛋全吃了
Ma, Robert's eating
all the deviled eggs,
他都不给我一个
won't give me any.
马戏团里从不让人吃饱饭
They don't feed us enough
in the circus.
嘿，爸爸是不是给杰弗里喝酒了？
Hey, did my father give Geoffrey
some wine today?
不，为什么？
No, why?
我抱他上床的时候，
他来一句
'Cause I was putting him
to bed, and he said,
“我爱你，兄弟”
"I love you, man. "
也许，你也该来点酒
Perhaps you would like
some wine.
嘿，听着
Hey, listen,
你知道你妈在那个派对上
跟我说什么了？
you know what your mom
told me at that party?
他们完全没朋友
They don't have
any friends.
你好像很吃惊
You sound surprised.
感觉有点悲哀
Well, it's kind of sad.
It's kind of sad.
对可能会成为他们朋友的人来说
Well, it's not sad
for the people
就不是悲哀了
who would have to be
their friends.
除了我们不得不做他们的朋友
Except we have to be
their friends.
-是有点悲哀
-是的
- That is a little sad.
- Yeah.
看着，我们是他们生活的全部
Look, we're their
whole lives!
我突然明白
如果他们的朋友多一些
It occurred to me
that if they had more friends,
他们也会少和咱们搅和
we'd have less them.
你准备好预算了吗？
Have you worked out
a budget for this?
好吧，别叨叨了
All right, break it up.
哦，你们想要什么？
咱们刚见过面的
Oh, what do you want?
We just saw you.
我们只是给你们带点剩下的食物
We just brought you
some leftovers.
剩下的东西
They don't qualify
as leftovers
还是热的？
if they're still warm.
咱们来看点精彩场面
Let's watch some highlights.
弗兰克，你看过这比赛了
Frank, you already
watched this game.
这样我就知道什么地方会精彩了
So I know how good
the highlights will be.
别因为说话把这破坏了
Let's not ruin these
by talking.
啊哼，那么
Ahem, so,
天，玛丽，
得到房子的所有权
gosh, Marie,
it must feel so liberating
-一定感觉非常解放吧？
-是的
- to own the house now, huh?
- Yeah.
想象你们有多少事情可以做了
Think of all the things
you can do now,
比如，喔，可以多请请客
like, gosh, you could
entertain more.
我们刚办了派对
We just had a party.
我们干什么的，
54号音乐工作室（1977-1986年曼哈顿一家传奇迪厅，
后1997年拉斯维加斯开了一家同名的俱乐部）？
What are we,
Studio 54?
不，说真的，
你们应该有自己的社交生活
No, really, you deserve
your own social life.
特别是现在房债都还清了
Especially now that all your house
obligations are over,
我们这边也能搞得定了
and we seem
to be managing.
现在是你们说
“你好啊，邻居！”
Now might be
the perfect time
的最好时机了
for you to say,
"Hi, neighbor!"
我需要朋友都在这了
I got all the friends
I need right here.
你看到了，黛比拉？
能重新招待客人
You see, Debra?
I would love to start
我当然喜欢了，
但要是客人来了，
entertaining again,
but if we have guests,
这个怎么解决？
what am I supposed
to do with this?
告诉他们你打赌输了，
Tell them
that you lost a bet,
只能再拾掇喂养他一年
and you've got to clean and feed him
for another year.
行了。
我们都知道
Come on.
We all know
弗兰克会很有趣的
that Frank can be
a lot of fun.
嘿，你知道还有谁很有趣吗？
Hey, you know who else
is a lot of fun?
-隔壁的毛尔家
-我喜欢毛尔家
- The Mauers next door.
- I like the Mauers.
不行
No can do.
-为什么？
-因为我最近说不定
- Why not?
- Because I may or may not
朝他们中哪个竖中指了
recently have flipped
one of them the bird.
怎么了？
他想把垃圾
What?
He was trying
扔咱们垃圾桶里
to put a piece of garbage
in our garbage can.
那也没必要竖中指吧
That's no reason
to flip them a bird.
嘿，我总不能让收垃圾的以为
Hey, I can't have
the garbage man thinking
我染头发了
I dye my hair.
哦，
Oh,
那这些很自然的了？
so then all that
is natural?
嘿，你知道谁很不错吗？
Hey, you know
who's cool?
-斯戴普家
-对呀，斯戴普家！
- The Stipes.
- Yes, the Stipes!
-谁？
-你记得……
- Who?
- You remember...
那些老……
友好的人
those old...
nice people
罗伯特第一次搬家时
一块住的人
that Robert lived with
first time he moved out.
他们要是还活着的话，
他们很友善的
If they're still alive,
they're very friendly.
我在五金店碰见过那个老公来的
I ran into the husband
in the hardware store.
-他还算不太讨厌
-看，看来你们
- He's actually not a jerk.
- See? It sounds like you guys
-在一块会玩得很开心的！
-很可能
- would have a blast together!
- You probably would.
怎么招呼他们，斯戴普家的？
But what are we supposed
to do with these Stipes?
我不知道
I don't know,
you could
你可以邀请他们过来
吃晚饭，喝点东西
invite them over
for dinner or drinks.
还可以玩
“猜猜我忘了什么了”
You could play
"Guess What I Forgot. "
下棋怎么样？
What about
a board game?
当然，好极了，下棋。
好主意
Yes, yes, a board game.
Great idea.
好主意，黛比拉
That's a good
idea, Debra.
弗兰克，我们要有伴了
Frank, we're having
company.
他们最好喜欢讲脏话
They better like
swearing.
我们该怎么做？
打电话给他们？
What should we do?
Should we call them?
越快越好
Only as soon as possible.
你知道谁有他们电话？
You know who has
their number?
罗伯特，他现在就住在你们房子里
Robert, who lives
in your house right now.
哦，我想好了一大堆菜单！
Oh, I have so many
menu ideas!
是啊，我们太兴奋了。
块从椅子上起来，爸
Yeah, we're all very excited.
Out of the chair, Dad.
-嘿
-快点
- Hey.
- Come on.
-我想看……
-出去
- I just wanna watch...
- Well, go outside.
吗在外面。
你们就要和新朋友玩了
Mom's outside. You're gonna go play
with your new friends!
他来了。走好
Here he comes.
There you go.
Yeah.
我知道这个舞
I know that dance.
这是“我想和雷嘿咻”的舞
That's the I-wanna-
have-sex-with-Ray dance.
这个是我
And here's my
“如果你坚持”的舞
if-you-insist dance.
你这是在……
别笑
What are you...
don't laugh.
嗯
Mmm.
真好。
感觉在约会
This is fun.
This is like a date.
是啊，除了约会的时候
你从来没到过第二阶段
Yeah, except on a date
you never got to level two.
嘿，行了
Hey, come on.
-行了。行了
-嗯
- Come on. Come on.
- Mmm.
-好吧
-嗨，亲爱的
- Okay.
- Hi, dears.
来，过去点
Come on, move over
还记得斯戴普家吧
You remember the Stipes.
看，哈里，我说了他在家！
See, Harry, I told you
he was home!
有什么需要帮忙的？
How may we help you?
哈里是你专栏的忠实支持者
Harry is a big fan
of your column,
不过来打个招呼
他是不会罢休的
and he wouldn't let up
until we swung by to say hello.
哈喽！
Hello!
很高兴见到你们。
谢谢你们过来
It's so nice to see you.
Thanks for dropping by.
嘿，雷，我告诉哈里
Hey, Ray, I told Harry
you would let him see
你可以让他今天就看明天的专栏
tomorrow's column today.
你知道我最喜欢什么？
You know what
I would really like?
如果你能告诉我明天的比分
If you told me
tomorrow's scores.
这样我就能去下注了！
Then I could make
some bets!
妈，你们在干嘛？
干吗把他们带这来？
Ma, what are you doing?
Why did you bring them here?
他们想见你
Well, they wanted
to see you.
好吧，但是黛比拉和我，
我们正……欢呢
Yeah, but Debra and I,
we were... happy.
-就5分钟
-不，妈，不不
- Just five minutes.
- No, Ma, no no.
你干吗这么大惊小怪的？
Why are you making
such a big fuss over it?
我们的朋友想见你
Our friends wanted
to see you.
我想他们看你们的
I want them to see you.
好吧，好
All right, okay.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
抱歉别人这么喜欢你
I'm sorry people
like you so much.
抱歉我为你骄傲
I'm sorry
that I'm proud of you.
抱歉我把你养成了好孩子
I'm sorry that I raised you
to be a nice boy.
-5分钟
-好的，好的
- Five minutes.
- Okay okay.
我告诉你，雷
I'll tell you, Ray,
你的生活真美妙
you've got the life.
体育作家
Sports writer.
他可以到处走
You get to go
to different places,
和体育明星见面
meet famous athletes.
也有时候比较闷些
Well, yeah,
there could be worse jobs.
嘿，雷
- Hey, Ray.
- Yeah.
嘿，告诉他们早几天
你见着谁了
Hey, tell him whom you met
the other day.
行了，爸
Come on, Dad.
不不，说吧，告诉他，
很有趣的！
No no, come on,
tell him, it's funny!
没什么。Evander Holyfield坐我边上
Nothing. Evander Holyfield
sat next to me.
-哇……
-Evander Holyfield！
- Holy...
- Evander Holyfield!
-我儿子和Evander Holyfield！
-哦天哪！
- My boy and Evander Holyfield!
- Oh my God!
-他是拳击手
-哦
- He's a boxer.
- Oh.
跟上点
Try to keep up.
那么，发生什么了？
So, what happened?
你知道，我就是……
我说：
You know, I just...
I said,
“嘿，怎么样？”
"Hey, how are you doing?"
他说：“还好啦。”
他人不错，挺不错的
He said, "Great. "
He's a good guy. He's a good guy.
-你和他说话了？
-是的，当然
- You talked to him?!
- Yeah, sure sure.
你知道，比方说：“打得不错，是吧？”
这类的话
You know, like, "Good fight, huh?"
That kind of thing.
-是啊
-是的是的
- Yeah.
- Yeah yeah.
喔，多好的故事啊！
Wow, that's a terrific story!
-好了，那么……
-嘿，爸
- Okay, so...
- Hey, Dad,
还记得我带你去全明星赛那次吗？
how about the time I took you
to the All-Star Game?
剑杂志社包间！
Yeah, press box!
哦，你个幸运的驴蛋！
Oh, you lucky bastard!
我们儿子肯定会喜欢的！
Our son
would love this!
他是个典型的体育疯
He's a regular
sports nut.
听着，听着，
等我从洗手间出来
Listen listen, so I'm coming back
from the bathroom,
我看到我爸站在那，
and I see my father
standing there,
我也不知道我在想什么，
and I don't know
what I'm thinking,
我偷偷走到他后面，
捅了他屁股一下
but I sneak up behind him,
and I kinda goose him a little.
他转过脸……
He turns around...
我捅的是Joe Garagiola（前棒球明星）！
I goosed Joe Garagiola!
当然了，从后面（屁股）看，
Of course, from behind,
我长得像Joe Garagiola！
I look
like Joe Garagiola!
-雷
-知道了。他也是个不错的人
- Ray.
- Yeah yeah. He's a good guy, too.
Joe人不错
Joe's a good guy.
哦，这多有趣啊！
真高兴你们来了
Oh, isn't this fun?
I'm so glad you came over.
-哦，我们也是
-是的，我们也是
- Oh, we are, too.
- Yeah, us too, us too.
哦，中国菜来了！
都有些什么？
Oh, Chinese here!
What do we got?
嘿，黛比拉，
拿叉子来！
Hey, Deb,
get some forks!
你知道来点什么会很好？
茶
You know what would be nice?
Some tea.
-我去做点茶
-我不介意喝点茶
- I'll make some tea.
- I wouldn't mind some tea.
嘿，你知道谁以前喜欢喝茶吗？
Joe DiMaggio（前棒球明星）
Hey, you know who used to like tea?
Joe DiMaggio.
-不！
-没错，咖啡先生
- No!
- That's right, Mr. Coffee.
你知道谁以前喜欢咖啡？
And you know who used
to like coffee?
T先生（前拳击手，演员）
Mr. T.
-嘿，swizzle（一种鸡尾酒，用小棒搅了喝）
-嘿，别歇着
- Hey swizzle.
- Hey, don't get comfortable.
斯戴普家又要上你爸妈那了
The Stipes are over
visiting your parents again.
我们得赶快走，
说不定他们又打算顺便过来了
We gotta get out of here
in case they decide to drop back over.
-孩子们怎么办？
-罗伯特会看孩子
- What about the kids?
- Robert's babysitting.
非走不可吗？
我刚到家
Do we have to go?
I just got home,
我累了。
躲起来不行吗？
I'm tired.
Can we just hide?
不不不，
别解扣子
No no no,
don't unbutton your shirt.
停下停下！
Stop it,
stop it, stop it!
你又不知道他们肯定会来
You don't know that they're definitely
gonna come over.
你也许还巴不得呢
You'd probably love it
if they did.
这样你又可以演一遍
“我漂亮的雷蒙德”
You could do a revival of your
one-man show "My Fair Raymond. "
嘿，我只是想帮你
Hey, I was trying
to help out.
结果我被他们缠住脱不了身
That's why I got
stuck there.
-你跑哪去了？
-卧在床上！
- And where did you disappear to anyway?
- I was in bed!
都大半夜了！
你们连个中场休息都没有！
It was midnight!
You don't even have an intermission!
你以为……你以为我喜欢那样吗？
What do you...
do you think I like that?
得了吧！
Come on!
斯戴普z一股阁楼味
Those Stipes smell
like the attic.
嘿，糖在哪？
孩子们想吃糖
Hey, where's the candy?
The kids want some candy.
孩子们知道晚上不许吃糖
The kids know
they're not supposed
好吧
- to have candy at night.
- Okay.
我想吃
I want candy.
冰箱上头，罗伯特
It's on top
of the fridge, Robert.
快点，快点，扣上，
该走了！
Come on, come on, button up,
we gotta get going!
-我们到餐馆给你打电话
-嘿，雷
- We'll call you from the restaurant.
- Hey, Ray,
你怎么不去见见你
最最要好的新朋友呢，
how come you're not going over
to see your new best friends
斯戴普家，哈？
the Stipes, huh?
妈从早到晚
Mom was just
going on and on
都在说他们有多喜欢
你的故事
about how they loved
your stories.
-没错吧，雷？
-我只是不想失礼！
- See, Ray?
- I was being polite!
你知道他们最开始是我朋友
You know they were
my friends first.
他们一准也会喜欢我的故事的
They would have loved
my stories, too.
只是他们来的时候
我碰巧在盆浴
I just happened to be in the sitz bath
when they came over.
好吧，罗伯特，
我们会早点赶回来的
All right.
Robert, we won't be late.
-快点，我们得走了
-我不饿
- Come on, we gotta go.
- I'm not hungry.
我在办公室吃了香蕉船
I had banana splits
at the office.
你们办公室有香蕉船？
You get banana splits
at the office?
我们就吃点开胃点，好了吧？
We'll just have
appetizers, all right?
怎么了？怎么了？
What? What?
-他来了！
-你上哪了？
- There he is!
- Where have you been?
别跟他们搅上。
我们要出去，明白？
Don't get sucked in.
We're going out, you understand?
-嗨！
-他来了，我们的人物!
- Hi!
- There he is, the man of the hour!
你剪头发了？
Did you get a haircut?
不，我梳了一下
No, I just
combed it today.
真不错
There he goes.
雷蒙德，我想你认识我们的儿子赛斯
Raymond, I want you
to meet our son Seth.
-雷・巴伦。终于见面了
-嘿，你好吗？
- Ray Barone. Finally we meet.
- Hey, how are you doing?
-我可是你的忠实读者
-谢谢
- I'm a big fan of yours.
- Thank you.
我们的文风非常相像
We have very similar
writing styles.
-Seth也是个体育作家
-哦
- Seth's a sports writer too.
- Oh.
多数是网络聊天室里
Well, mostly
in internet chat rooms,
体育广播节目里我常打进电话
and I call in
to all the sports radio shows,
你很可能听到过我……
Massapequa的赛斯
You probably heard me...
Seth from Massapequa.
哦，是。
非常好，老兄
Oh, yeah.
Great, man,
好极了。
真替你高兴
that's great.
Good for you.
-听着，我们正要出去
- Listen, we were on our way out, right?
- Yes.
等等，你们去哪？
Wait wait wait,
where are you going?
我们只是去吃个晚饭。
请不要拘束
We're just going out to dinner.
You guys make yourselves at home.
玛丽知道东西都在哪
Marie knows
where everything is.
她放的
She put it there.
我读了你今天的专栏。
非常棒，棒极了
I read your column today.
Great, just great.
哈利说你比Lupica（体育专栏名作家）更出色
Harry says you're better
than Lupica.
-哦
-谢谢
- Oh.
- Thank you, thank you.
-我喜欢你写的棒球
-谢谢
- I love your baseball stuff.
- Thanks.
只是也许你可以对大都会队
更客观点
Except you could be a little more
objective about the Mets.
-什么？
-雷
- What?
- Ray. Ray.
你感觉像有些动机不纯
You seem to have
a real axe to grind there.
唔……
Well...
你要知道他们给我工钱
是要我写自己的想法
you understand that they pay me
to write my opinions,
而不是要客观
not to be objective.
你知道，我发现
You know, I find
在体育撰稿上，
你要是不肯出重拳
that in sports writing
if you pull your punches,
你就会成挨打的人
you're gonna end up
the one getting hit.
哦
Oh.
这才是专业人士，儿子
Now that's a pro, son.
这就是为什么你还在网络里混
That's why you're still
on that internet.
嘿，向大师鞠躬了
Hey, I bow
to the master.
好的
Okay.
嘿，丽塔，哈利。
真抱歉昨晚没见到你们
Hey, Rita, Harry.
Sorry I missed you last night.
嘿，罗德尼！
那么……
Hey, Rodney!
So...
给赛斯讲讲
你给我们讲的故事
Tell Seth that story
you were telling us
那只在Kingdome体育馆
爬到你腿上的松鼠
about the squirrel that ran up your leg
at the Kingdome.
哦，太有趣了！
Oh, that was so funny!
哦，你跟他们讲松鼠的故事了，哈，雷？
Oh, you told them
the squirrel story, huh, Ray?
那不是Chuck Wilson的故事吗？
Isn't that
Chuck Wilson's story?
那不是Chuck Wilson的故事
It's not
Chuck Wilson's story.
-是的！
-不是
- Yes, it is!
- It's not.
我来给你们讲个故事
I'll tell you a story.
我最近被头公牛顶了……
I was recently
gored by a bull...
那可大过松鼠2000倍
which is about 2000 times
larger than a squirrel.
你知道，他们非法骑牛……
You see, they were having
an illegal rodeo...
哦，在这了！
Oh, here it is!
雷蒙德，介意吗？
Raymond,
would you mind?
-你想给我照张像？
-是的
- You wanna take my picture?
- Yes.
-好吧，当然
-好极了
- Okay, yeah.
- All right.
给，罗德尼
Here, Rodney,
介意给我们大家伙照张像吗？
would you mind getting
a picture of all of us?
为什么介意呢？
Why would I mind?
给我的伤痛再加点羞辱
Add a little insult
to my injury.
我也想一起来。
快点，弗兰克
I wanna get in on this.
Come on, Frank.
我也来，不过我最好坐下
I'm in, but I better
sit down,
除非你们想拍我的Garagiola
unless you wanna get
a shot of my Garagiola.
非比寻常的时刻。
我要贴到我的网站上
This is phenomenal.
I'm posting this on my website.
-嘿，对好焦了？
-放心吧
- Hey, you got us in focus there?
- I sure do.
大家一起念：
“雷蒙德”
Everybody say, "Raymond. "
雷蒙德！
Raymond!
真美
Beautiful.
-黛比呢？
-我听到车库门响了
- Where's Deb?
- I heard the garage door.
-不，不
-哦，雷蒙德
- Oh, no.
- Oh, Raymond,
留下陪我们
stay with us.
你想见她什么时候不行啊？
You can see her anytime.
嘿，嘿，
你去哪？
Hey hey hey,
where are you going?
我去吃饭。
我本想叫你一起去的
I'm going to eat.
I would ask you to come along
不过我看到你有了一个女朋友了，
三个男朋友
but I see you have a girlfriend,
and three boyfriends
-还有一个女朋友
-没事的
- and another girlfriend.
- Look, it's okay.
他们说我可以交别的朋友
They said I could see
other people.
-好吧，对不起
-你有问题
- Okay, I'm sorry.
- You have a problem.
把钥匙给我。
这种状态你不能开车
Give me your keys.
You can't drive in this condition.
行了。
我没问题
Come on.
I don't have a problem.
不能这样过了。
你和你父母的联系
This can't keep happening.
You have a sick connection
已经到了变态的程度了。
明白吗？变态！
to your parents.
You understand? Sick!
好吧。
我们已经讨论过这个了
All right.
We've already been over that.
你变本加厉了！
你父母的关心还不够？
You're worse now!
You don't get enough attention
你还得再找一副？
你有病！
from your parents, so you have to get
an extra set? You're sick!
好吧，我再也不这样了。
我很抱……
Okay, I won't do it anymore.
I'm sorr...
啊！怎么样吧？
Ah! What?
我们走，我们溜出去。
我们去吃饭
Let's go, we'll sneak out.
We'll go eat.
嗨，亲爱的
Hi, dears.
-嗨
-什么事情？
- Hi.
- What's going on?
不，没什么
No, nothing.
-没事吧？
-很好，没事
- Everything all right?
- Fine, yeah yeah.
找着你在找的美国汽车协会的
小册子了吗，黛比拉？
Did you find that AAA booklet
you were looking for there, Debra?
你有病！
You're sick!
好吧，继续找
All right,
keep looking.
听我说，我想你和斯戴普家的
Listen, I think
you and the Stipes
也许接下来的时候
应该去你那边
should go to your house,
maybe, for the rest of the night,
因为黛比拉和我说好了出去吃饭的
'cause Debra and I
made plans to go out and eat.
我知道，我知道，
可是你就不能和我们带几分钟吗？
I know, I know, but couldn't you
just spend a few minutes with us?
你几乎没和赛斯说什么话
You hardly talked
to Seth at all.
妈，我都不认识赛斯，好吗？
Ma, I don't even
know Seth, okay?
我甚至都不认识斯戴普家的。
他们是你们的朋友
I don't even know the Stipes.
The Stipes are your friends.
你为什么不去和你们的朋友
在一起？
Why don't you just go
and be with your friends?
因为我们需要你，雷蒙德
Because we need you,
Raymond.
什么意思你需要我？
为什么？
What do you mean,
you need me? Why?
爸爸在里面。
他很有趣
Dad's in there.
He's funny.
不，他没有
No, he's not.
你就不能进来几分钟吗？
Could you come in
for just a few minutes?
不不不
No no no.
妈，够了，
求你了，够了
Ma, it's enough,
please, it's enough.
-好吧
-好的
- Okay okay.
- Yeah.
没关系。
我能理解
It's fine.
I understand.
我只是想看你和他们在一起
It's just that I like
to see you with them,
因为我不再能看到你那样子了
because I don't get to see
you like that anymore.
-哪样子？
-唔
- Like what?
- Well,
如今你在家里
when you come over
to the house now,
只是吃吃东西、看看比赛
it's just to eat
or watch a game.
而看你说话时的那种兴奋
It's different
to see you
感觉不一样
excited when
you're talking.
我喜欢这感觉
I like it.
好吧
Okay.
我才咱们都该进去了
I guess we should all
go back inside.
真的？是吗？
Really? Yeah?
我猜可以
I guess it's okay.
哦，你真是好儿子。
谢谢，亲爱的
Oh, you're such a good son.
Thank you, honey.
他回来了！
He's coming back!
必须响应大家的要求
Gotta give the people
what they want.
人们通常误以为
A common misconception is
that a bull will charge
看到红色会让公牛攻击
when shown
the color red.
事实上，是运动
Actually, it's motion.
雷。谢天谢地！
Ray. Thank God!
来，坐下
Here, have a seat.
没时间了，哈里。
我们得走了
No time for that, Harry.
We gotta go,
-要迟到了
-哦，是的
- we're gonna be late.
- Oh, yeah, you're right.
-什么迟了？
-我们要带你父母
- Late for what?
- We're taking your parents
参加海外退伍军人的
to the big
senior jamboree
老年大狂欢！
at the VFW!
喔，老年狂欢！
Wow, senior jamboree!
太好了！
对你好极了，妈
That's perfect!
That's perfect for you, Ma.
你会很开心的！
快去，去吧
You'll have fun!
You go, you'll have fun. Go ahead.
你也应该去，雷
You should go too, Ray.
-什么？
-是的，你刚刚对你妈说
- What?
- Yeah, you were just
你想多陪陪他们
telling your mom that you wanted
to spend more time with them.
剑和我们一起来吧，雷
Yeah, come on with us, Ray.
他们今晚提供免费检查眼睛！
They're giving
free eye tests tonight!
不！不，我是说
No! No, I mean,
我们还要出去吃饭的，不是吗？
we wanted to go out
to eat, right?
但你的响应大家的呼声
But you gotta give
the people what they want.
来吧，雷。
包你喜欢
Come on, Ray.
There will be refreshments.
-快点，快点
-有多糟？
- Come on, come on.
- How bad is this thing?
听起来像噩梦。
我才不去！
Sounds like a nightmare to me.
I'm not going!
再见
Bye-bye.
希望你喜欢跳舞，雷蒙德！
I hope you like
dancing, Raymond!
-中餐？
-好极了！
- Chinese?
- Love it!
jojoba
yettoreturn@hotmail.com